genesis.com 2018-12-30

# Genesis Privacy Policy | Genesis USA

Your privacy is important to Genesis Motor America ("Genesis" "we," "us" or "our") and its affiliate companies, as is your trust in Genesis products and services. We strive to protect your online privacy, while providing an enjoyable website experience that offers information, products, and services that are relevant and useful to you. The purpose of this Genesis Motor America Website Privacy Policy (this “Privacy Policy”) is to notify and inform you of how we collect, use and share information across our US websites or applications, including [Genesis.com](https://www.genesis.com/) and [MyGenesis.com](https://www.genesismotorsusa.com/owners) (collectively, the “Site”). 

**This Privacy Policy describes:**

  * •  The information that we collect
  * •  How information is collected
  * •  How we use the information
  * •  How we may share information with third parties
  * •  The security of your information
  * •  Your information choices

**USER CONSENT AND INCORPORATION**

PLEASE REVIEW THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY. By using the Site, you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy and our Website [Terms of Use](https://www.genesis.com/us/en/terms-conditions.html) and consent to our collection, use, disclosure and retention of your information as described in this Privacy Policy to the maximum extent permitted by law. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY PART OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY OR OUR TERMS OF USE, THEN PLEASE DO NOT USE THE SITE. The Site and information on it is intended for use and access by U.S. residents only. Genesis does not knowingly collect, process, access or intend to access the personal information of persons residing outside of the U.S., including in Europe and China. If you do not reside in the U.S., you should stop accessing these sites. Instead, you should visit the Genesis-affiliated website that is applicable to your country or region. 

**VEHICLE TECHNOLOGIES AND SERVICES; THIRD PARTY SITES**

Vehicle Technologies and Services  
We also offer certain vehicle technologies and services to make our vehicles safer, more environmentally friendly, more convenient and more fun to drive. Some of these technologies and services collect, use or share information that is collected, generated, recorded or stored by Genesis vehicles. This Privacy Policy applies only to the collection, use and sharing of information collected on the Site and does not apply to collection of information by those vehicle technologies and services. Our privacy practices with respect to our vehicle technologies and services are described in our Genesis Vehicle Owner Privacy Policy and our [Genesis Connected Services Subscriber Privacy Policy](https://owners.genesis.com/us/en/connected-services-subscriber-privacy-policy.html). Should you use such vehicle technologies and services, we encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies. 

Third Party Sites  
We may offer links to or from the Site to other websites within the Genesis and Hyundai family as well as to websites, services and resources operated by third parties. We offer links to third party websites so that you can conveniently visit our vendors and advertisers or locate other content likely to be of interest to you. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, content or policies of websites operated by third parties and urge you to inquire about their privacy and information sharing practices before providing any Personally Identifiable Information. In the event that you provide Personally Identifiable Information to any third party website or service, you understand that Genesis is not responsible for such third parties’ use or misuse of your Personally Identifiable Information. You further acknowledge and agree that Genesis shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such content, goods or services available on or through any such third party website, service or resource. 

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

You can visit the Site to read about our vehicles or use our online tools without providing any Personally Identifiable Information (other than, in some cases, your zip code). You may also choose to participate in activities and obtain services on the Site for which we may collect Personally Identifiable Information. We also collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information automatically when you use the Site.

“Personally Identifiable Information” is information that may be used to identify or contact a specific person. Personally Identifiable Information may include: (1) identifier data (name, address, city, state, zip code, email address, telephone number, and IP address); (2) demographic data (such as age range, gender, birth month); (3) vehicle information (vehicle identification number (VIN), make, model, model year, selling retailer and date of purchase or lease); and (4) credit card number and payment card information. 

“Non-Personally Identifiable Information” is information that, by itself, does not identify the individual, such as the operating system you are using, the date and time stamp of your visit, referring URLs, your Internet service provider, browser type and related browser data, the pages you visit and purchase history. 

**HOW INFORMATION IS COLLECTED**  
Information You Provide To Us  
We collect information that you provide to us when you use the Site. The information that we collect and how we process it depends on how you use the Site. We may collect Personally Identifiable Information when you participate in certain activities on the Site or request certain services, including:

  * •  When you register or create an account
  * •  When you make brochure and information requests, order vehicle parts and accessories and request to receive site announcements and special offers
  * •  When you participate in promotional activities, such as surveys, sweepstakes, contests, special events, blogs and chats
  * •  When you contact us
  * •  When you otherwise voluntarily provide your Personally Identifiable Information

Information We Collect Automatically  
We also collect certain information from users of the Site automatically when they visit. We may collect such information in the following ways: 

_Cookies_  
We may collect certain preference information of website users through the use of HTTP cookies which are small files stored on your web browser in order to optimize the design of the Site. Cookies enable us to track and aggregate user behavior data so that we may better target the interests of our users and enhance their experience on the Site. You can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some website features or services may not function properly without cookies. 

_Web Beacons_  
Some of our web pages, commercial email messages and/or newsletters may contain electronic images known as web beacons, which are also called single-pixel GIFs. Web beacons collect information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view and a description of the page on which the web beacon resides. Web beacons are a technique we may use to enhance and personalize the Site and the products and Services we offer, to provide product information and advertisements that are more relevant to your interests, compile aggregated statistics about the usage of the Site and to track the number of users who have opened and acted upon our commercial email messages. 

_Web Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising_  
A number of technologies exist to analyze use of the Site, assess consumer behavior and serve relevant ads to consumers online. Genesis employs a variety of these technologies, including web beacons, third-party analytics services, and third party interest-based advertising services. These technologies allow us to assess consumer behavior and to understand how we can better serve our customers. Many of these technologies are provided to Genesis via third party providers specializing in behavioral marketing and consumer behavior. For example, our analytics service providers may use cookies or other technologies to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information about Site visitor behavior. The information generated by your browser use, stored via cookies, log files, and other information sources (including IP address), is transmitted to our analytics service providers. We may also obtain information from our advertising partners about your interaction with our marketing campaigns across websites, devices, platforms, and environments. This information is then used to evaluate visitors’ use of the Site, to compile statistical reports on website activity for Genesis, and to review the efficacy of marketing campaigns. We may aggregate this Non-Personally Identifiable Information with other information for analytics purposes. Our third-party advertising partners on this Site may also use browser and device tracking technologies (HTTP cookies, web beacons, advertising IDs, etc.) to collect and measure non-personally identifiable data about your browsing behaviors. We use these interest-based advertising vendors serve relevant advertising across the Internet and other platforms and environments (including television).If you would like to know more about interest-based advertising, or opt-out of interest-based advertising conducted by our partners, please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://optout.aboutads.info/). 

_Third Party Advertisers_  
Some banner ads provided by third parties may be displayed on the Site. These ads contain cookies and may also contain web beacons. Unlike cookies and web beacons used by Genesis in content it controls on the Site, cookies or web beacons received with banner ads are collected by our advertisers and we do not have access to this information. We use third parties to serve some or all of the advertisements that are placed within the Site and they may use information (not including Personally Identifiable Information) about your visits to the Site and other websites to assist in serving advertisements to you. These companies may employ cookies, web beacons and action tags to measure advertising effectiveness. They may share certain information with their clients such as date and time the banner ad was shown you, the specific ad shown and the IP address. 

_Log Files_  
Like most websites, we collect log information to analyze trends, administer the sites, track users’ movement around the Site and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in improving the sites. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

Information We Obtain from Other Sources  
Genesis may also obtain information about you and your vehicle in a number of other ways. For example, we may obtain information about you or your vehicle when you provide it to us at an event such as an auto show, from business reply cards, sweepstakes entries, test-drive incentive applications, surveys, vehicle sales records and other public sources. Such information may include: 

  * •  Contact information (name, address, city, state and zip code, email address, telephone number)
  * •  Vehicle information (vehicle identification number (VIN), make, model, model year, selling retailer, date of purchase or lease, etc.)
  * •  Demographic information (age range, marital status, household composition, etc.)
  * •  Non-credit-related marketing information (when you plan to purchase or lease, the vehicle in which you are interested, etc.)
  * •  Relationships you have with Genesis affiliates and business partners such as SiriusXM and roadside assistance programs

In addition, Genesis retailers (which are all independently owned and operated) and other sources that provide lists of potential vehicle purchasers or current owners may provide to us the information they have regarding you or your vehicle. We use this information to serve your needs through better customer service and to advise you of our products and services. 

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION**   
We may use your information individually or combine it with other information to generate aggregate statistical information. The primary uses of your information include: 

  * •  To fulfill a specific product or service you have requested
  * •  To provide product information
  * •  To operate, improve, enhance and personalize the Site and the products and services we offer, and to give each user a more consistent and personalized experience when interacting with us
  * •  To answer your questions or address any complaints you may have made
  * •  To evaluate candidates as they apply for an employment position with Genesis
  * •  To let you know about special discounts or added vehicle services or functions
  * •  To show advertisements that are more relevant to your interests and to evaluate our marketing campaigns across platforms and environments
  * •  For research and analysis
  * •  For customer service, security, to detect fraud or illegal activities, or and for archival and backup purposes
  * • To enforce our Terms of Use or other applicable policies

**HOW WE MAY SHARE INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES**

Third Party Service Providers, Affiliates and Marketing Partners  
Genesis may share Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information, including website user or vehicle owner information, with third parties including our service providers, affiliates (including Hyundai Motor America), authorized retailers, licensees, and suppliers so that they can provide services on our behalf. In addition, user or vehicle owner data may be used by our suppliers to provide services for Genesis and by our business partners, including marketing and promotional partners, to conduct joint marketing programs with Genesis, show you advertisements about our products and services on third party sites, and to offer you other valuable products and services. If you wish to opt-out of receiving third party commercial communications, you may exercise this right by following the opt-out procedures contained in any email or written communication Genesis sends you or by following the procedures set forth in the “Unsubscribe or Opt-Out” section of this Privacy Policy. 

Programs  
Genesis may invite you to participate in promotional activities, such as surveys, sweepstakes, contests, special events, blogs and chats (“Programs”). These Programs are oftentimes co-marketed with an unaffiliated Genesis business partner. If you participate in a Program, we may use Personally Identifiable Information you provide. For example, we may send you email messages to invite you to join a contest Program. Your Personally Identifiable Information may also be shared with our business partner and may also be used by our business partner if you indicate your interest in receiving communications directly from that company. If you elect to receive communications from our business partner, your information will be used by that company in accordance with its policies and this Privacy Policy will not apply to that company’s use of your information. Sometimes the rules, terms and conditions or disclaimers that apply to a particular Program include information on how we may use the Personally Identifiable Information that you provide to us through your participation in the Program. If there is a conflict between the rules, terms and conditions that apply to a particular Program and this Privacy Policy, those applying to the particular Program will govern. Please review all of the information about a Program before you provide us (or our business partners) with any Personally Identifiable Information. 

For Audit and Legal Purposes  
Genesis may disclose any Personally Identifiable Information or Non-Personally Identifiable Information collected to any person performing audit, legal, operational or other similar services for Genesis. Genesis may also disclose any Personally Identifiable Information or Non-Personally Identifiable Information when required to do so by subpoena, court order, or warrant. Genesis will also disclose any Personally Identifiable Information or Non-Personally Identifiable Information deemed necessary to protect the safety of an individual, the public, or the security and reliability of Genesis and the Site. 

Participating Vendors  
Some of our websites offer opportunities to make purchases online from special participating vendors. On websites with online purchase opportunities for products and merchandise, we may also give participating vendors the order information and authorization for the merchant bank. Any time you order from a participating vendor, that vendor will automatically have all the information related to the order. Participating vendors may use that information to advise you directly of other products and offerings that they provide. 

Credit Card Companies; Third Party Payment Services; Third Party Promotional Sites  
In some cases, we use third party payment and transaction services to facilitate your transactions and process your orders. In such cases, we will share your Personally Identifiable Information and credit card information with third party payment services companies solely for the purpose of completing the transaction or processing your order. In some cases, we will share your Personally Identifiable Information and credit card information with third parties who may offer you a gift or promotional offer as a result of your interest. As in any transaction, your credit card company will have all relevant information about the name of the vendor, item(s) purchased, date of purchase and total cost. Genesis will not otherwise provide any Personally Identifiable Information to your credit card company. 

Public Postings  
You should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose information, personal or otherwise, online in any community area (whether through Genesis websites or any other service available online), that information can be collected and used by others. Accordingly, you should use caution when sharing any Personally Identifiable Information or other sensitive information with others in any community area (whether through Genesis websites or any other service available online). 

Changes in Corporate Structure  
In developing our business, we might sell certain assets, or the company, or parts of it, may be sold, merged or otherwise transferred. In such transactions, user information, whether Personally Identifiable Information or otherwise, may be one of the transferred assets. 

With Your Consent  
Other than the cases above, we won’t disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose unless you consent to it in some way, including by your continued use of the Site after notice. 

**THE SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We use security policies, procedures and tools which are designed to safeguard data submitted through the Site against accidental or intentional loss, theft, unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification and disclosure. However, the security of information transmitted through the Internet can never be guaranteed regardless of the level of security. We are not responsible for any interception or interruption of any communications through the Internet or for changes to or losses of data. Users of the Site are responsible for maintaining the security of any password, user ID or other form of authentication involved in obtaining access to password protected or secure areas of any of the Site. In order to protect you and your data, we may suspend your use of any of the Site, without notice, pending an investigation, if any security issue arises. Access to and use of password protected and/or secure areas of any of the Site are restricted to authorized users only. Unauthorized access to such areas is prohibited and may lead to criminal prosecution or civil action. 

**YOUR INFORMATION CHOICES**

You may choose to share your Personally Identifiable Information with us. However, your participation in using our websites and providing Personally Identifiable Information is completely voluntary. You can unsubscribe and opt-out to certain communications and access, or update and delete your contact information, by contacting us at the email address, number or address specified below. 

Accessing and Updating Your Information  
If you register for an account on [MyGenesis.com](https://owners.genesis.com/us/en/index.html), you can access and update certain information we have relating to your online account by signing into your account and going to the “My Account” section of the Site. You may also update or delete your contact information by emailing us at [consumeraffairs@genesismotorsusa.com](mailto:consumeraffairs@hmausa.com), by calling (800) 633-5151 or by writing us directly at: Genesis Motor America/Phoenix, P.O. Box 83835, Phoenix, AZ 85071-3835. 

Unsubscribe or Opt-Out  
Genesis offers you the opportunity to opt-out from receiving commercial email, calls, or mail from Genesis about our products and services. 

  * •  You may opt-out of emails at any time by using the unsubscribe mechanism within the email. The unsubscribe mechanism allows you to manage your subscription preferences to email alerts and special offers. Notwithstanding the above, this mechanism does not allow you to opt-out of receiving non-commercial email, such as registration confirmation, vehicle updates and responses to direct requests.
  * •  You also may call, email, or write to us directly if you wish to opt out or request that we cease sending you commercial or other information via call, mail or email. Such requests can be made by emailing us at [consumeraffairs@genesismotorsusa.com](mailto:consumeraffairs@hmausa.com), by calling (800) 633-5151 or by writing us directly at: Genesis Motor America/Phoenix, P.O. Box 83835, Phoenix, AZ 85071-3835.

At the time information is collected from you, other choices you have about how the information may be used may be explained. 

If you have opted out of receiving future emails from us, we will implement your opt-out request within ten (10) business days of receiving the opt-out request. If you have opted out of receiving future promotional materials by regular mail, we will implement your opt-out request within a commercially reasonable time. In those instances, we will retain your information in a “do not promote” file in our database, and you will receive no further communications from us as required by law. 

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as Senate Bill 27, or “Shine the Light” law California residents with whom we have an established business relationship are entitled to request and receive, free of charge, once per calendar year, a copy of Genesis California Information Sharing Disclosure Notice about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses in the previous calendar year. You may call (800) 633-5151 or email us at [consumeraffairs@genesismotorsusa.com](mailto:consumeraffairs@hmausa.com) to request a copy. We will provide the requested information to you at your email address in response. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” law requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

We do not knowingly collect or maintain Personally Identifiable Information from any person under the age of thirteen (13) as they are not of driving age. No parts of our Services are directed to or designed to attract anyone under the age of thirteen (13). 

**DO NOT TRACK**

The Site does not support Do Not Track at this time. Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that you can set in your web browser to indicate that you do not want certain information about your webpage visits collected across websites when you have not interacted with that service on the page. For all the details, including how to turn on Do Not Track, visit [donottrack.us](https://www.eff.org/issues/do-not-track). 

**TERMS OF USE & DISPUTE RESOLUTION**

This Privacy Policy is incorporated in and a part of the Terms of Use that govern your access to and use of the Site. By agreeing to the Terms of Use, you are also agreeing to the provisions set forth in this Privacy Policy. You also agree that any disputes you may have with us will be governed by Section 4 of the Terms of Use, entitled “Dispute Resolution Policy: Binding Arbitration.” This includes, but is not limited to, disputes we may have with each other arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy. All other provisions of the Terms of Use, including the General Provisions at Section 22, shall otherwise govern our relationship unless expressly modified or addressed within this Privacy Policy. 

**EFFECTIVE DATE AND CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

The Effective Date of this Privacy Policy is set forth at the top of this webpage. Genesis reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Genesis will use, share, and disclose all personal and other user information in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the information is collected. We will post any changes to this Privacy Policy on this page so check back frequently so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Continued use of this Site following changes to these terms will mean that you accept the changes. 

**HOW TO CONTACT US WITH QUESTIONS**

Please email us at [customercare@genesismotorsusa.com](mailto:customercare@genesismotorsusa.com) or by calling (844) 340-9741, or write us at Genesis Customer Care, P.O. Box 20850, Fountain Valley, CA 92728-0850 if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy.
